There are two mathematical theorems that are
هناك نظريتان رياضيتان يتم مناقشتهما
commonly discussed when looking at sampling distributions,
عادة عند النظر إلى توزيع العينات.
the Law of Large Numbers and the Central Limit Theorem.
قانون الأعداد الكبيرة ونظرية الحد المركزي.
First, let's go through the Law of Large Numbers.
في البداية، دعونا نتناول قانون الأعداد الكبيرة.
This theorem makes a lot of sense and it tells us that if
هذه النظرية تجعل كثير من الأمور تبدو منطقية وتخبرنا أنه
we choose the right statistics to estimate a parameter,
إذا اخترنا الإحصاءات الصحيحة لتقدير المعلمة،
the larger our sample size,
كلما كان حجم عينتنا أكبر،
the closer the statistic gets to the parameter.
كلما اقتربت الإحصاءات من المعلمة.
Makes a lot of sense, right?
هذا يبدو منطقيًا، أليس كذلك؟
If you want to know the mean of a population and you estimate it with the sample mean,
إذا كنتم تريدون معرفة متوسط السكان وتقديره عن طريق متوسط العينة،
the larger the sample size,
فإنه كلما كان حجم العينة أكبر،
the better your sample mean will be,
كلما كان متوسط العينة أفضل،
estimating the population mean.
في تقدير متوسط السكان.
So you might be wondering,
لذا ربما تتساءلون،
what makes a statistic the right estimate of a parameter?
ما الذي يجعل إحصاء تقدير المعلمة صحيحًا؟
There are a number of ways to estimate parameters.
يوجد عدة طرق لتقدير المعلمات.
In the instructor notes below,
في ملاحظات المعلم أدناه،
I've provided links to some of the most popular methods.
وفرت لكم روابط لبعض الطرق الأكثر شيوعًا.